A Guide to the Singleton P. Moorehead Papers, 1923-1972
Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
- 3, 27 Notebooks (Box 3)
  - Notebook 3 1923, 124 pages (20 cm) (Volume 24)
    Labeled Venice 1923, contains sketches and notes on proportions. It is mostly blank.
  - Notebook 17, 86 pages (20cm) (Volume 25)
    Contains notes on Moorehead's work on the restoration of Colonial Williamsburg. It is mostly blank with multiple leaves removed.
  - Notebook 19, 100 pages (20 cm) (Volume 26)
    List of Architectural details with reference location. Arranged alphabeticall by detail type.
  - SPMOOREHEAD portfolio, 37 cm (Folder 27)
    Leather binding boards from a portfolio.
- 4, 18 Folders (312 items) (Box 4)
  Contains a mixture of his work for Colonial Williamsburg and student work, as well as a number of reproductions of european art likely from his trip to europe as a grad student.
  - 20 items (Folder 1)
    Contains photostats of Monogram ciphers, with envelope from the New York public library from which the research was procured.
  - Circa 1950s, 31 items (Folder 2)
    Contains information on, drawings, and some blueprint elevations of a proposed 17th theater.
  - 1952, 25 items (Folder 3)
    Contains photostats of research done for the proposed 17th century theater.
  - 1953, 9 items (Folder 4)
    Contains research and sketches done for an 18th century fair.
  - 14 items (Folder 5)
    Contains reprodutions of various european art.
  - 38 items (Folder 6)
    Contains reproductions of european art, notably several etchings by Rembrandt.
  - 14 items (Folder 7)
    Contains depictions of greek vases on linen paper.
  - 1923-1927, 46 items (Folder 8)
    Contains sketches of European architecture from Moorehead's student trip abroad and other school work.
  - 10 items (Folder 9)
    Contains original watercolors by Moorehead.
  - 1926-1928, 6 items (Folder 10)
    Contains some student work and other drawings.
  - 2 items (Folder 11)
    Contains a reproduction and sketch from New Orleans, LA.
  - 1922-1925, 17 items (Folder 12)
    Contains sketches of the American West.
  - 4 items (Folder 13)
    Contains photographs and a photostat, including a portrait by Thomas L. Williams.
  - 5 items (Folder 14)
    Contains miscelleous sketches.
  - Circa 1927, 8 items (Folder 15)
    Contains Christmas cards and designs created by Moorehead.
  - 8 items (Folder 16)
    Contains sketches of heraldic designs from English abbys.
  - 11 items (Folder 17)
    Contains elevations and blueprints. The locations are unclear.
  - 50 items (Folder 18)
    Contains sketches and photostats of various architectural details. The related locations are unclear.
- 5, 282 items (Box 5)
  Contains two portfolios of art reproductions from his trip to europe, the second is of monted clipped reference illustrations of interiors and crests. One published art book with 26 reproductions and a sample of a Mary Cassett Art book to be published in 1942. As well as 1 folder containing 3 copies of the Boston Evening Transcript real estate section from 1927 February 19 plus the first six pages of an additional copy. The Front page story is of a building project with the Harvard Building Trust and the firm Kilham, Hopkins, and Greeley which Moorehead worked for briefly.
  - Circa 1927, 78 items (Volume 1)
    Contains reproductions of European art, likely gathered during a student trip to Europe.
  - 1927, 5 items (Folder 2)
    Contains 3 and a half copies of the Boston Evening Transcript dated 1927 February 19. The front page story is of a building project at Harvard.
  - Circa 1940, 1 item (Volume 3)
    Sample Art book of Mary Cassatt's work by Adelyn D. Breeskin, set to publish in 1942
  - 66 pages (197 items) (Volume 4)
    Contains mounted and loose illustrations of French buildings, interiors, and crests.
  - George Duplussis OEUVRE de A. MANTEGNA 1878, 68 pages (59 cm) (Volume 5)
    A collection of reproductions with introduction. The binding is in poor condition.
- 6, 14 folders (694 items) (Box 6)
  A mixture of reference material; photographs and negatives (Black and White 35mm), index cards, articles, catalogs, and coorespondance. All material seems to relate to Moorehead's work at Colonial Williamsburg.
  - 1924, 1 item (Folder 1)
    Contains the series "Furniture of historic types" by Arthur DeBles, from International Studio magazine.
  - 1923-1972, 61 items (Folder 2)
    Contains bulletins, magazine ariticles and coorespondance.
  - Circa 1940s, 54 items (Folder 3)
    Contains black and white photographs of buildings and farm scenes.
  - 74 images (Folder 4)
    Contains photographic negatives on 35mm film.
  - 1923-1924, 10 items (Folder 5)
    Contains correspondence, a guidebook, and the article "A Painting and a contract" by Guy Eglington clipped from orginal source.
  - 1941-1961, 14 items (Folder 6)
    Correspondence regarding Mooreheads membership to the American Insitute of Architects.
  - 1953-1954, 12 items (Folder 7)
    Contains handwritten notes on Fairs, lists of reference material, and a basic architectural report.
  - Circa 1940-1960, 4 items (Folder 8)
    Contains book catalogs, and lists of reference material in the form of a descriptive bibliography.
  - 115 images (Folder 9)
    Contains a series of photographic prints on card stock of architectural details from Mexico and Rome.
  - 1947, 2 items (Folder 10)
    Correspondence from the office of John D. Rockefeller Jr. and an article referencing a restoration project in New York, Sunnyside, that Moorehead consulted on.
  - 313 items (Folder 11)
    Contains a series of index cards carrying history, descriptions, citationsm, and other reference material.
  - 16 items (Folder 12)
    Contains lists of books of interest, correspondance, and magazines. As well as an example photo book of the work by Perry, Shaw, and Hepburn.
  - 1955, 1 item (Folder 13)
    May issue of "Art in America" that contains an article by Moorehead on architectural restoration.
  - Circa 1952, 17 items (Folder 14)
    Contains reference bibliographies and a copy of "Glassmaking at Jamestown" by J.C. Harrington.
- 7, two wooden index card boxes (1268 items) (Box 7)
  The cards are a mix of handwritten and typed reference notes set up in alphabetically order as quick reference for a variety of subjects relating to the restoration of historic Williamsburg. They include citations, quotations, drawings, and some direct information about the titled subject.
- 8, one cardboard index card box (989 items) (Box 8)
  The cards are a mix of handwritten and typed reference notes set up in alphabetically order as quick reference for a variety of subjects relating to the restoration of historic Williamsburg. They include citations, quotations, drawings, photographs, and some direct information about the titled subject.
- 9, two woden index card boxes (1018 items) (Box 9)
  The cards are a mix of handwritten and typed reference notes set up in alphabetically order as quick reference for a variety of subjects relating to Williamsburg during the 18th century. They include citations, quotations, drawings, photographs, and some direct information about the titled subject.
- 10, two wooden index card boxes (1175 items) (Box 10)